AUDREY

POINSOT

CONTACT INFO

Affiliation INIRA Saclay, Paris Saclay University, Ekimetrics

E-mail audrey.poinsot@ekimetrics.com

Website https://audreypoinsot.github.io/academic_website/

ABOUT ME

I am a second-year Ph.D. student at INRIA (Paris, France) under the supervision of Marc Shoenauer and Alessandro Leite.

At the **intersection of Causality and Machine Learning**, my current research project aims to improve decision-support tools with a specific interest in **robustness** and **uncertainty**. Having worked as a consultant for a year before starting my Ph.D., my research is driven by concrete applications.

My goal is to democratize the use of causal reasoning in statistical analysis for decision-making by providing tools to create value easily, sustainably, and fairly.

EXPERIENCE

PH.D. STUDENT

2022-today

INRIA Saclay, Paris Saclay University | Gif-sur-Yvette, France

- Thesis topic: "Causal Uncertainty Quantification under Partial Knowledge and Small Data Regimes"
- Supervised two Master students on Causal Data Generation projects

DATA SCIENTIST CONSULTANT

2021-2022

Ekimetrics | Paris, France

- Interpretability and Time Series: Decomposition of marketing actions' uplifts with SHAP on predictions of time series revenues
- Few-shot Learning in NLP: Use of semi-supervised methods for Aspect Based Sentiment Analysis applications

DATA SCIENTIST INTERN

2020

Schlumberger | Cambridge, UK

- Performed data-driven prognostics for Survival Analysis
- Resulted in the deployment of the solution on more than 14 equipment

DATA SCAN TOOL ENGINEER INTERN

2019

Schlumberger | Paris, France

- Build a physical model of signal propagation in transmission lines to generate a dataset
- Applied Machine Learning algorithms to detect and locate failures

EDUCATION

MSc in Applied Mathematics for Data Science

2020-2021

CentralSupelec, Paris Saclay University | Gif-sur-Yvette, France

- Graduated with a GPA of 4.2, top 10%
- Thesis in collaboration with the Paris BNP AI Lab: "GNNs for Financial Product Recommendation"

Undergraduate engineering cycle

2017-2019

CentralSupelec, Paris Saclay University | Gif-sur-Yvette, France

• Graduated with a GPA of 4, top 10%

Preparatory classes

2015-2017

Lycée Pierre de Fermat | Toulouse, France

PUBLICATIONS

Articles

A. Poinsot and A. Leite (2023). "A Guide for Practical Use of ADMG Causal Data Augmentation". In: Workshop on the pitfalls of limited data and computation for Trustworthy ML, ICLR 2023. URL: https://openreview.net/forum?id=kBcAZcKypug.

CONFERENCES

ICLR WORKSHOP ON PITFALLS OF LIMITED DATA AND COMPUTATION FOR TRUSTWORTHY ML

May 2023

Kigali, Rwanda

• Presented a poster

THEMATIC QUARTER ON CAUSALITY

Spring 2023

Paris Grenoble, France

- Chaired some sessions
- Presented a poster

ELLIS DOCTORAL SYMPOSIUM

Sept 2022

Alicante, Spain

Presented a poster

MACHINE LEARNING SUMMER SCHOOL (MLSS22)

June 2022

Krakow, Poland

• Presented a poster

SKILLS

Program Languages

- Professional level: Python (PyTorch, sklearn, numpy, ...)
- Intermediary level: R, Java, C++

Data Science Frameworks

Slurm, Azure Databricks, Dataiku, Google Cloud

Languages

- French (native)
- English (full professional proficiency)
- Spanish (basic)

REFEREES

Alessandro

Researcher Team TAU, INRIA Saclay Leite

alessandro.leite@inria.fr

Marc Shoenauer

Research Director Team TAU, INRIA Saclay marc.schoenauer@inria.fr

Head of Innovaltion, Research & Devlopement Ekimetrics Nicolas Ches-

neau

nicolas.chesneau@ekimetrics.com